epsilon.com 2015-12-10

# Privacy Policy

Information Collection and Use  
Information Sharing and Disclosure  
Choices (Opt-Out and Access)  
Cookie Practices  
Online Targeted Advertising  
U.S. Safe Harbour and Dispute Resolution  
Links to Third Party Sites  
Content Sharing Features  
Participation in Online Forms  
Security  
Changes to this policy  
Contact Us

Last Revised: March 05, 2015

This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by Epsilon on [www.epsilon.com ](http://www.epsilon.com/ "Epsilon")and other Epsilon affiliate sites that display or link directly to this Policy (collectively, “Sites”). This Privacy Policy is designed to ensure that visitors to our Sites understand how and why Epsilon collects and uses information provided by users of our Sites.

This Privacy Policy also does not apply to information not collected on Epsilon Sites that may be stored in Epsilon databases. For more information on Epsilon databases, and for information on how to opt-out, please visit our[ Consumer Preference Center](http://www.epsilon.com/consumer-preference-center/ "Consumer Preference Center"). 

This Privacy Policy does not apply to information collected by our Shopper’s Voice Survey. For information on the privacy practices of Shopper’s Voice, please visit the applicable [U.S. privacy policy](http://www.epsilon.com/privacy-policy/ "Privacy Policy") or [ Canadian privacy policy](http://www.shoppersvoice.ca/privacy-policy/ "Canadian privacy policy"). 

Epsilon has received TRUSTe’s Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy statement and our practices have been reviewed for compliance with the TRUSTe program viewable on the validation page available by clicking the TRUSTe seal. If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact [TRUSTe here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request "TRUSTe website"). The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through the website www.epsilon.com.

**Information Collection and Use**

**Epsilon Information Collection Practices**  
Epsilon collects and stores the information you voluntarily provide to us through our Sites. For instance, you provide contact information to us through the Contact Us form and other forms we may ask you to complete. This may include such personal information as your name, the company you work for, business title, postal address, email address, telephone number, and other information. In addition, Epsilon automatically collects certain information from your computer and stores it in log files. This information may include your web browser, IP address and pages visited on our Sites. We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to improve services we offer you, and to improve marketing, analytics, or site functionality. You must be 18 years of age or older to submit registration information to our Sites.

**Epsilon Information Use Practices**  
Epsilon will use the personal information collected to market to you per the preferences you specified when you registered on our Sites. Our marketing efforts include business-to-business direct marketing and promotional information related to Epsilon’s marketing services.  
Epsilon will not use your information except as described in this Policy in effect at the time of collection. 

Epsilon uses the information we collect to fulfill requests you have made to Epsilon, such as to communicate with you, respond to your inquiries and provide newsletters or updates. We may also use your information to make our Sites easier for you to use and to inform you of service and product updates, whitepapers, new products, market research opportunities and other related information from Epsilon.

Epsilon uses your browser information to analyze trends, administer our Sites, track users’ activities on our Sites, help us understand the parts of our Sites visited most often and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use in improving our Sites.

Epsilon may also obtain personal information from you regarding any job postings you may apply to, such as name, email address, mailing address, employment history and any other personal information contained in your resume/C.V. that you submit through our Sites. We may use your personal information to send you a welcoming email to verify your username and password for employee recruitment purposes and to respond to your requests for information.

**Information Sharing and Disclosure**  
Epsilon may share your personal information with our affiliate companies who may be able to address or respond to your inquiries. All Epsilon affiliates are committed to protecting your privacy and upholding the commitments made in this Policy.

Epsilon may share your information with our service providers who perform services on our behalf. All Epsilon service providers are committed to protecting your privacy and will uphold the commitments made in this Policy. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us. In some instances, our services providers use framing techniques to collect your personal information while preserving the look and feel of our site.

Epsilon may share your information with another company in relation to a sale or consolidation of Epsilon’s assets, provided, however, that such company agrees to honor all of the privacy commitments set forth in this Policy.

We reserve the right to disclose your personal information as required by law, court order or other valid legal processes. We also reserve the right to disclose your personal information when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request.

Epsilon may transfer your personal information from your country of residence to countries that may not require the same level of data protection for your personal information as provided in your country of residence. 

Epsilon will uphold the practices as noted in this privacy policy and comply with, as applicable, the U.S. – E.U. Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S. – Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as detailed below under [U.S. Safe Harbour and Dispute Resolution](http://www.epsilon.com/privacy-policy/#U.S.%20Safe%20Harbor).

Epsilon may share your personal information to any other party with your prior consent.

**Choices**

**Opt-Out of Epsilon Corporate Communications**  
Epsilon maintains contact lists to communicate with our clients and prospects. Individuals must affirmatively ask to join one or more of our email lists by registering on our Sites. All email messages sent to these lists include an opportunity to unsubscribe or opt-out of future email messages. You may also request to be removed from future email messages by contacting us via email or by using the links below:  
North America: [privacy@epsilon.com](mailto:privacy@epsilon.com "privacy email") or [opt-out online](http://info.epsiloninteractive.com/p/WebSiteLeads/Epsilon_Opt-Out "opt-out online")  
Asian-Pacific region: [apac-privacy@epsilon.com](mailto:apac-privacy@epsilon.com "apac privacy") or or [opt-out online](http://info.epsiloninteractive.com/p/WebSiteLeads/Epsilon_Opt-Out "opt-out online")  
European Union and EEA: [emeaprivacy@epsilon.com](mailto:emeaprivacy@epsilon.com "privacy email") or opt-out online ([Français](http://form.emeaupdates.epsilon.com/emeamainpc_fr/emeamainpc_fr.aspx "Francaise") and [Deutsch](http://form.emeaupdates.epsilon.com/emeamainpc_de/emeamainpc_de.aspx "Deutsch"))

Epsilon also maintains a postal mailing list to communicate with our clients and prospects. You can request to be removed from our mailing list by sending your name and postal address to us via email or postal mail to one of the addresses listed below under [Contact Us](http://www.epsilon.com/privacy-policy/#contact%20us "Contact us").

This Privacy Policy does not apply to information not collected on Epsilon Sites that may be stored in Epsilon databases. For more information on Epsilon databases, and for information on how to opt-out, please visit our [Consumer Preference Center](http://www.epsilon.com/consumer-preference-center/ "Consumer preference center").

Epsilon retains your information for as long as you have an open and active account profile with us or as needed to provide you the services you requested. We will retain and use your information to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements. If you choose to opt-out of our communications, Epsilon will retain the minimum amount of your information necessary to maintain a record of your opt-out.

**Access to Personal Information**  
At Epsilon, we believe it is important to provide consumers with clear information about the data available in our Epsilon databases. If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, delete or ask to have it removed by emailing or contacting us. U.S. residents may request access to learn what information Epsilon has about your household in our Epsilon databases using our Marketing Data Summary Request Form. For non-U.S. residents, please contact us via email or postal mail to one of the addresses listed below under [Contact Us](http://www.epsilon.com/privacy-policy/#contact%20us "Contact us").  
We will respond to your requests within 14 business days.

**Cookies**  
Cookies are small text files that store data using your web browser to make your browsing experience easier and faster. We, and our third party service providers who assist with managing our Sites, use cookies, web beacons and similar technologies on our Sites. We use Performance and Functionality cookies, as described below, to improve the performance of our Sites and to make our Sites more user-friendly.

Epsilon respects enhanced user privacy controls. We support the development and implementation of a standard “do not track” browser feature, which provides customers with control over the collection and use of information by third parties regarding their web-browsing activities. At this time Epsilon does not respond to DNT mechanisms. Once a standardized “do not track” feature is released, Epsilon intends to adhere to the browser settings accordingly.

The European Union Directive 2009/136/EC, amending Directive 2002/58/EC on Privacy and Electronic Communications (otherwise known as the e-Privacy or Cookie Directive), and laws in EU countries implementing such Directive require user consent before a site may place cookies and other similar technologies on your device or to use such technologies to access information on your device. Where required, we provide notice to consumers of our cookie practices upon visiting our Sites and by using our Sites you agree to the use of cookies in Europe, as detailed below.

**Cookies Used by Epsilon on Our Sites**  
Performance Cookies: These cookies collect information about how visitors use our Sites for web analytics purposes, for instance which pages visitors go to most often and error messages received. These cookies are only used to improve how our Sites work and your experience on our Sites; they do not track your browsing activity on other websites. By using our Sites, you agree that we can place these types of cookies on your device.

Functionality Cookies: These cookies allow our Sites to remember choices you make (such as remembering your user name and password, language preference or the region you are in) and provide enhanced, more personalized features. These cookies may also be used to remember changes you have made to text size, fonts and other personalizations. They may also be used to provide services you have requested, such as keeping you logged in to your account as you browse the internet. These cookies do not track your browsing activity on other websites. By using our Sites or by signing up for an account with us, you agree that we can place these types of cookies on your device.

Tracking Cookies: For information on cookies that are used for tracking, please see below under **Online Targeted Advertising**.

**Modifying Your Browser Settings**  
You can modify your browser settings at any time, including setting your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, giving you the choice to decide whether or not to accept it. If you reject cookies, you may still use our Sites, but the functionality of some areas may be limited.

Below are links to information on managing your cookie preferences with common browsers and links for more information on cookie practices:  
• [Google Chrome](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en "Google chrome")  
• [Mozilla Firefox](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences?redirectlocale=en-US&redirectslug=Enabling+and+disabling+cookies "Mozilla firefox")  
• [Microsoft Internet Explorer](http://support.microsoft.com/Error?aspxerrorpath=/kb/283185 "Microsoft internet explorer")  
• [Safari](http://support.apple.com/kb/PH11913 "Safari")  
• [Google Analytics](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245 "Google analytics ")  
• [More information on cookies](http://www.iabeurope.eu/files/6813/7042/5310/Internet_Cookies_-_Increasing_and_enhancing_your_internet_surfing_experience.pdf "More information")

For any questions related to our web technologies, you may contact us via email at [ privacy@epsilon.com](mailto:privacy@epsilon.com).

**Other tracking technologies**  
Other technologies such as beacons, tags and scripts are used by Epsilon and our partners marketing and analytics partners and service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an aggregated basis.

Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity use local storage objects (LSOs) such as Flash to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing Flash LSOs. To manage Flash LSOs please [click here](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html "flash settings").

**Online Targeted Advertising**

As you browse the internet, you may see advertisements on the web pages you visit. Some of these ads are targeted based on a variety of factors, such as websites you visit, perceived interests, and demographic information. This practice is called Online Targeted Advertising. We work with advertising partners to enable the delivery of relevant messages to the right consumers while protecting consumer privacy and offering choices about participating in such activities. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you with Online Targeting Advertising. Our Sites may also engage in Online Targeted Advertising and when visiting our international Sites, where required, you will see a notice that provides information on our use of cookies on that specific Site. Online Targeted Advertising does not result in more ads, rather the ads you see will be more relevant to you. 

For more information regarding Epsilon’s [ Online Targeted Advertising ](http://www.epsilon.com/privacy-policy/#online%20targeted%20advertising)activities and to opt-out of Online Targeted Advertising, please visit the [Epsilon Consumer Preference Center](http://www.epsilon.com/consumer-preference-center/ "Consumer preference") or visit the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/ "Opt out page").  
Canadian consumers can opt-out [here](http://youradchoices.ca/choices "opt out") and EU consumers can opt-out [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/ "opt out")

For any questions related to our web technologies, you may contact us via email at [ privacy@epsilon.com](mailto:privacy@epsilon.com)

**U.S. Safe Harbor and Dispute Resolution**

Epsilon complies with the U.S. – E.U. Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S. – Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. When you register with Epsilon, you agree that the personal information collected may be transferred across international borders to complete your request.

Epsilon Data Management, LLC and Alliance Data FHC, Inc., trading as Epsilon International, annually certify that they adhere to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access and enforcement. Please see the U.S. Department of Commerce’s website <http://export.gov/safeharbor> for details regarding our compliance.

As part of our participation in Safe Harbor, we have agreed to the TRUSTe dispute resolution process for disputes relating to our compliance with the Safe Harbor Privacy Frameworks. If you have any complaints regarding our compliance with the Safe Harbor Frameworks you should first contact us at [ privacy@epsilon.com](mailto:privacy@epsilon.com).

If contacting us does not resolve your complaint, you may raise your complaint with TRUSTe by:

Internet: <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>

Mail: WatchDog Complaints, TRUSTe  
835 Market Street, Suite 800  
San Francisco, CA, USA 94103

Fax: 415-520-3420

If you are mailing or faxing TRUSTe to lodge a complaint, you must include the following information:  
• The name of the company  
• The alleged privacy violation  
• Your contact information  
• Whether you would like the details of your complaint shared with the company

For information about TRUSTe or the operation of TRUSTe’s dispute resolution process, visit TRUSTe’s [website](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request "TRUSTe's website") or request this information from TRUSTe at the address listed above. The TRUSTe dispute resolution process will be conducted in English.

**Links to Third Party Sites**  
Our Sites contain links to unaffiliated third party sites. Epsilon and its affiliate Sites do not endorse or make any representations about any third party sites (or any information, software or other products or materials found there) to which our Sites might link. This Privacy Policy does not apply to the information collection and use practices of third party sites. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of these unaffiliated third party sites to understand their data collection and use practices.

**Content Sharing Features**  
Our Sites include social media sharing features, such as LinkedIn and Twitter buttons, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. These features may collect your IP address and which page you are visiting on our Sites. Social media features are governed by that social media company’s privacy policy.  
We may also allow you to email useful information from our Sites to a friend or colleague. If you choose to do so, we may ask you to provide your full name and email address, as well as your friend’s complete email address. We will send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the Site, except where prohibited by law. Your friend or colleague may contact us at [privacy@epsilon.com](mailto:privacy@epsilon.com "privacy") to opt out.

**Participation in Online Forums**  
Our Sites provide opportunities to participate in various online forums (for example, the Epsilon blog A ‘Brand’ New View). If you contribute any content to an online forum, you retain your rights to any content you post. However, by posting content on or through an online forum, you grant Epsilon a worldwide, non-exclusive, royalty-free license (with the right to sublicense) to use, copy, reproduce, process, adapt, modify, publish, transmit, display and distribute your content in any and all media or distribution methods (now known or later developed) for any and all purposes.

Any content you post to an online forum may be publically viewed and used by anyone on the internet. You are responsible for any content you post, and for any consequences thereof, including the use of your content by other users. To protect your privacy, Epsilon reminds you not to submit personal information in a public forum.

By posting, you agree not to post any content that (i) is unlawful, harmful, threatening, abusive, harassing, tortious, defamatory, vulgar, obscene, libelous, invasive of another’s privacy, hateful, or racially, ethnically or otherwise objectionable; (ii) you do not have a right to make available under any law or under contractual or fiduciary relationships; (iii) infringes any patent, trademark, trade secret, copyright or other proprietary rights of any party; or (iv) contains software viruses or any other computer code, files or programs designed to interrupt, destroy or limit the functionality of any computer software or hardware or telecommunications equipment.

Epsilon may pre-screen, refuse, or remove any content that you post. We may also modify or adapt your content in order to transmit, display or distribute it.

Epsilon does not control the content posted by public users to our Sites and, as such, does not guarantee the accuracy, integrity or quality of such content. Under no circumstances will Epsilon be liable in any way for any user-contributed content, including, but not limited to, any errors or omissions in any content, or any loss or damage of any kind incurred as a result of the use of any user-contributed content.

To request removal of your personal information from our online forums, or to notify us of a posting that violates our rules for posting in Epsilon’s online forums described above, please contact us at [privacy@epsilon.com](mailto:privacy@epsilon.com "privacy"). If we are unable to remove your personal information, we will let you know that we are unable to do so and why.

**Security**  
Epsilon uses physical, electronic and administrative safeguards designed to protect your personal information against loss, misuse or alteration. All information is stored securely and may only be accessed by employees with a legitimate business need to access the information. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure and cannot guarantee its absolute security.

**Changes to this Policy**  
Epsilon may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time. If Epsilon identifies new material purposes for the information already collected from you, we will seek your express consent prior to using the information we have already collected from you for any new purpose. Any other changes to this Privacy Policy will be posted here and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what changes have been made in how we collect, use and disclose your information. 

You should bookmark and periodically review this page to ensure that you are familiar with the most current version of this Policy. You can determine when this Policy was last revised by checking the “Last Revised” legend at the top of this Policy. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective.

**Contact Us**

To ask questions about Epsilon’s Privacy Policy or to request more information on Epsilon’s privacy practices, email us or send correspondence to:

**North America**  

Epsilon  
Privacy Manager  
2550 Crescent Drive  
Lafayette, CO 80026

**EU and EEA region**  

Epsilon International  
Attention: Privacy  
Teddington House  
67 Broad Street, Teddington  
Middlesex TW11 8QZ, UK

**Asian-Pacific region**  

Epsilon  
Attention: Privacy  
Room 2601, 26/F  
Hopewell Centre  
183 Queen’s Road East  
Wanchai, Hong Kong
